<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<country>

	<intro><![CDATA[ Supporting cancer control in East, South-East and South Asia<br>Mumbai Hub, Global Initiative for Cancer Registry Development ]]></intro>
	<population>90796000</population>
	<hdi>medium</hdi>

	<incidence>
		<cases>125000</cases>
		<cum_risk>14.5</cum_risk>
	</incidence>

	<mortality>
		<deaths>94750</deaths>
		<cum_risk>11.8</cum_risk>
	</mortality>

	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
		<li>Viet Nam is an initial focus country of the Mumbai Hub </li>
		<li>A strategic plan of action has been developed to address priorities </li>
		<li>Funding to support the implementation is needed </li>
	</ul>
	]]></description>

	<registries></registries>

	<core_functions>
		<training>1</training>
		<directed_support>1</directed_support>
		<networks>1</networks>
		<cancer_control>1</cancer_control>
	</core_functions>

	<need><![CDATA[<p> Viet Nam is a densely populated country undergoing social and economic transition. The 90 million inhabitants, despite benefiting from a higher average life expectancy than most other countries in East Asia and the Pacific, face disparities in health. Modelling regional data from the existing cancer registries yields an estimated 125,000 new cases and 95,000 deaths from cancer occurring each year. The Ministry of Health has taken important steps to improve prevention, early detection and treatment through the establishment of a National Cancer Control Program in 20XX.  </p> 

	<p> Reliable data as the foundation for effective cancer planning is valued by stakeholders in Viet Nam but is currently lacking in many parts of the country. Nine cancer registries exist, evenly divided in the three regions. While Vietnamese cancer registries have many strengths, only two of the nine (Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City) are deemed to be of high-quality</p>

	]]></need>

	<solution><![CDATA[<p> Cancer registration in Viet Nam holds promise. Although faced with challenges, there is a strong history of performance by several registries. In particular, methods to collect and manage data in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City have been successful. Qualified staff in these registries have been proposed to assist other registries with technical support placing greater importance on the need to establish a national network. Another significant opportunity is the commitment of the government in understanding that cancer registries are a key component to a strong cancer program. </p> 

	<p> Established to eliminate barriers, the Global Initiative for Cancer Registry Development is an international partnership working with countries to produce data that leads to successful cancer control programs. Six IARC Regional Hubs serve to provide a connected system arranged to link needs with regional support mechanisms. The Mumbai Hub, based at the Tata Memorial Hospital, functions as this resource for East, South-East and South Asia. Viet Nam has been selected as one of the initial priority countries of the Hub. </p>

	]]></solution>

	<impact><![CDATA[<p>With a dedicated purpose, the Global Initiative for Cancer Registry Development is addressing information inequities that ultimately help save lives and reduce the suffering from cancer in the most vulnerable populations. To deliver on this vision, the Mumbai Hub has formed collaborative partnerships that promote the sharing of knowledge and its uptake in cancer program planning. Implementing this model in Viet Nam will lead to: 
   <ul>
	 <li>A stronger evidence base for cancer control planning and monitoring, allowing targeting investments in the most needed areas </li>
	 <li>An increase in the number of high quality population-based cancer registries </li>
	 <li>An accurate profile of the types of new cancer cases and deaths by age, sex, year and region  </li>
	 <li>Optimal use of cancer data through stronger, more direct linkages between decision makers, clinicians, researchers and the people of Viet Nam </li> </li>
	 <li>Greater opportunities in research to describe patterns and investigate causes of cancer  </li>
	 <li>A larger group of trained staff with new skills in data collection, analyses and dissemination </li>
	 <li>A documented evaluation of what works in cancer surveillance with recommendations for broader application to other types of non-communicable diseases  </li>
	 <li>Increased access to emerging technologies, especially electronic health systems </li>
	</ul></p>
	]]></impact>

	<action><![CDATA[Initial assessments and site visits conducted by the International Agency for Research on Cancer and other partners of the Global Initiative for Cancer Registry Development, identified a main set of actions. With resources, the following are targeted:  
	<ol>
		<li>
			TRAINING 
			<ul>
		 		<li>In the methods in data collection and management. Hanoi and Ho Chi Min City registry training can first be supplemented through the Mumbai Hub courses and then 	transferred onto other registry staff. </li>
		 		<li>Viet Nam registries need to increase their capacity to conduct analyses through basic courses in descriptive cancer epidemiology. </li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>
			DIRECTED SUPPORT 
			<ul>
			 <li>An important area is to assist in improving the coverage of the newly established Danang Registry.  </li>
			 <li>An evaluation of the Hue Cancer Registry for the central region of the country is needed to ascertain completeness. </li>
			 <li>Lack of available mortality data is an issue in Viet Nam. To improve this, a pilot plan has been developed for the Ho Chi Minh City Registry. </li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>
			CANCER CONTROL
			<ul>
			 <li>Provide regular policy briefings on the findings and implications of cancer trends in their region.</li>
			 <li>Perform new in-depth analyses, especially in the area of cancer projections to assist with planning.</li>
			 <li>Establish a clear policy for reporting cancer to assist in the ability of registries to collect data. </li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>
			NETWORKS
			<ul>
				<li>Develop a joint work plan between the two technical centres – Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City – to help with training registry staff across the country.</li>
				 <li>Form a national registry association to help facilitate the exchange of information.  </li>
	 			<li>Identify leads to liaise with other countries in the region and with the Mumbai Hub. </li>
	 		</ul>
	 	</li>
	 </ol>
	]]></action>

	
</country>