<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<country>

	<hub_name>Izmir hub</hub_name>
	
	<hub_centers>
    <![CDATA[
    <p> <a data-fancybox="gallery" href="data/hubs/IZMIR/DSC_4000.JPG"> <img src="data/hubs/IZMIR/DSC_4000.JPG" width="100%"> </a> The Regional Hub in Izmir was established in 2013, in collaboration with the Turkish Ministry of Health, and is located at the Cancer Registry in Izmir, Turkey. The Hub is tasked with assisting cancer registries in the 27 countries of Northern Africa (Algeria; Egypt; Libya; Morocco; Sudan; Tunisia), Central Asia (Kazakhstan; Kyrgyzstan; Tajikistan; Turkmenistan; Uzbekistan) and Western Asia (Armenia; Azerbaijan; Bahrain; Georgia; Iraq; Israel; Jordan; Kuwait; Lebanon; Oman; Qatar; Saudi Arabia; Syrian Arab Republic; Turkey; United Arab Emirates; Yemen).</p>

	<p> High-quality PBCR are operational at the national level in the high-income countries of Bahrain, Kuwait, Israel and Qatar, while there are equivalent regional PBCR in Algeria, Egypt, Libya, Saudi Arabia, Tunisia and Turkey. There are, however a number of countries where PBCR are active, or registry development is underway, in Western Asia (Georgia, Jordan, and Lebanon) and in Northern Africa (Morocco and Sudan). Further, there have been recent calls for IARC and the Izmir Hub to help support the establishment of PBCR in several Central Asian countries, including Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan and Uzbekistan (Figure 6: Registration status in the Izmir Hub for North Africa, Central Asia and West Asia). 

	<a data-fancybox="gallery" href="data/hubs/IZMIR/Astana_20140926_122547 (1).jpg"><img src="data/hubs/IZMIR/Astana_20140926_122547 (1).jpg" align="left" width="100%"></a>
	</p>
]]></hub_centers>
	<hub_pi>
    <![CDATA[ <p>Principal Investigator <br/>
Dr. Sultan Eser, MD, PhD <br/>
Director, Izmir Cancer Registry <br/>
Associate Professor, Hacettepe University <br/>
Institute of Public Health <br/>
Izmir, Turkey <br/>
[Insert short bio] </p>  ]]></hub_pi>
	<canreg_experts>
    Dr. Amani A. Albasmi (Kuwait), Cankut Yakut (Turkey), Anton Ryshov (Ukraine?)..</canreg_experts>
	<planned_activities>
    <![CDATA[ <p> With the WHO Country Office Syria, support is being provided for re-establishing cancer registration, planned to start off as hospital based network, in Syria. </p>
  
  <p> A CanReg training workshop for the Syrian team is scheduled in Iran in May 2017, hosted by the Cancer Institute Iran (by Dr Kazem Zandehdel). </p> ]]></planned_activities>
	
</country>