<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<country>

	<hub_centers><![CDATA[
<p> <a data-fancybox="gallery" href="data/hubs/LA/El Savador Workshop Faculty Oct2014.jpg"><img src="data/hubs/LA/El Savador Workshop Faculty Oct2014.jpg" align="left" width="50%"></a> The IARC Regional Hub for Cancer Registration for Latin America was established in 2014. During discussions with key stakeholders, a model was selected that aims to capitalize on the expertise available in several countries through a shared mechanism. The approach calls for a central coordinating centre (INC / Argentina) acting in conjunction with ‘contributing centres’ to collectively deliver the activities for the Hub. A Steering Committee from the relevant organizations would serve as a means to provide local oversight for this model.</p>

<p>The coordinating centre for the Hub is based in the National Cancer Institute (INC) of Argentina in Buenos Aires. The Hub provides assistance to the 19 Spanish and Portuguese speaking countries in North America (Mexico), Central America (Costa Rica; Cuba; El Salvador; Guatemala; Honduras; Nicaragua; Panama) and South America (Argentina; Bolivia; Brazil; Chile; Colombia; Ecuador; Paraguay; Peru; Uruguay; Venezuela). </p>

<p> Collaborative centres are being selected to provide technical expertise and experience, with consideration to other factors such as a balance between cancer registries and national cancer institutes. Collaborative centres will be expected to provide mentorship and contribute to training activities. Initially, three to four centres will be designated as ‘collaborating centres.’ The region also benefits from established cancer registry networks. Notably, the Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) along with the consortium groups REDEPICAN and the Network of National Cancer Institutes -RINC (Red de Institutos Nacionales de Cáncer).  They have acted to deliver support to the region. </p>

<p> <a data-fancybox="gallery" href="data/hubs/A/Latin American Cancer Control Leadership Forum 2.jpg"><img src="data/hubs/LA/Latin American Cancer Control Leadership Forum 2.jpg" align="right" width="50%"></a> The Ibero-American Network of Cancer Epidemiology and Information Systems (REDEPICAN) was created in 1984 through a broad cooperation agreement between 19 Latin American countries, Spain and Portugal. The overall objective of REDEPICAN is to facilitate collaboration for cancer epidemiology and information systems among Ibero-American countries. Similarly, the RINC cancer registry working group, based in Brazil, has a mandate to promote the development of cancer surveillance systems for the RINC countries, with the purpose to broaden knowledge on cancer burden for appropriate cancer control actions. Discussions regarding the integration of efforts between the Hub and these groups will be an essential element of the development of the Hub.</p>

<p>High-quality PBCR at the national level are available in two countries (Costa Rica and Uruguay), although there are regional equivalents in many countries including organized networks of registries in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia and Ecuador alongside regional registries in Cuba and Peru. There also ongoing efforts to establish PBCR in Bolivia, Guatemala, Mexico and Paraguay. (Figure7: Registration status in the Latin American Hub) </p>
]]></hub_centers>
	<hub_pi><![CDATA[ Principal Investigator: Dr. María Graciela Abriata <br/>
Coordinadora del SIVER-Ca<br/>
Sistema de Vigilancia Epidemiológica y Reporte del Cáncer <br/>
Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (INC)/Ministerio de Salud de la Nación  
 ]]></hub_pi>
	<canreg_experts>Betty Carballo (Argentina), Dr Claudia Uribe (Colombia), Gonçalo Forjaz de Lacerda (Acores) </canreg_experts>
	<planned_activities><![CDATA[  <p> With the support of PAHO, a training course (intermediate level -data analysis) for cancer registries is scheduled in Quito, Ecuador in May 2017. <br/><img src="data/hubs/LA/Panama Training Nov 2015_LA Hub 2.jpg" width="100%"> </p> 	]]></planned_activities>
	
</country>