<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<country>

	<hub_centers>
    <![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with the International Network for Cancer Treatment and Research (INCTR) and based in Oxford (UK), a “virtual” Hub was established during 2012 by an agreement with the African Cancer Registry Network (AFCRN), acting as a consortium to provide Hub activities for PBCR in Sub Saharan Africa. While all registries in countries within the region are eligible for AFCRN membership, the registry must be population-based, achieving at least 50% coverage of the target population and invited to join following a consultant visit of evaluation. The role of INCTR is provision of a secretariat and coordinating centre for the Network, which assists in implementing the programme of activities for the Hub.</p>

<p>The activities of the African network are guided by the advisory group (steering committee). The current members are: Jean-Marie Dangou (Regional Advisor on non-Communicable Diseases, WHO-AFRO); Dr Anne Korir (regional representative for Africa, IACR); Freddie Bray (Head of Cancer Surveillance Section, IARC); and Julie Torode (Director Advocacy and Programmes / Deputy CEO, UICC).</p>

<p>The Hub covers 48 countries in the four regions of sub-Saharan Africa: East Africa (Burundi; Comoros; Djibouti; Eritrea; Ethiopia; Kenya; Madagascar; Malawi; Mauritius; Mozambique; Rwanda; Seychelles; Somalia; South Sudan; Tanzania; Uganda; Zambia; Zimbabwe), Middle Africa (Angola; Cameroon; Central African Republic; Chad; Congo, Democratic Republic; Congo, Republic of; Equatorial Guinea; Gabon), Southern Africa (Botswana; Lesotho; Namibia; South African Republic; Swaziland) and West Africa (Benin; Burkina Faso; Cape Verde; Cote d'Ivoire; The Gambia; Ghana; Guinea-Bissau; Guinea; Liberia; Mali; Mauritania; Niger; Nigeria; Sao Tome and Principe, Senegal; Sierra Leone; Togo).</p>

<p>The longstanding high-quality registries in the region are in Uganda (Kampala) and Zimbabwe (Harare), with Malawi (Blantyre) and the South African Republic (RSA) acquiring CI5 status in the last Volume, the latter (the PROMEC registry) covering the rural 1.3 million population in the former-Transkei region of the Eastern Cape Province. The countries where PBCR are developing and producing data include highly-populated Nigeria in the North, Kenya, Ethiopia and Tanzania in the East, the Gambia and Guinea in the West, while there are efforts to start an expansion of PBCR in RSA and Mozambique. There are a considerable number of registry developments ongoing within the 22 present AFCRN members across 19 countries, although there remains some 18 countries in the region where there are no data or the status of registration is presently unknown (Figure 5: Registration status in the Sub Saharan Africa Hub).</p>

<p>For Further information: <br/> 	
INCTR,<br/>
African Cancer Registry Programme,<br/>
Prama House,<br/>
267 Banbury Road,<br/>
Oxford,<br/>
OX2 7HT,<br/>
UK<br/>
Email: admin@afcrn.org<br/>
http://afcrn.org/ </p>]]></hub_centers>
	<hub_pi>
    <![CDATA[ <p> Principal Investigator <br/>
Dr. Max Parkin <br/> 
Honorary Senior Research Fellow, Oxford University <br/>
Senior Visiting Scientist, IARC </p>

<p>Dr Donald Maxwell (Max) Parkin was born in 1944, and graduated summa cum laude in medicine at Edinburgh University in 1968, where he later took an MD (1985). After an early career in clinical medicine, he moved to Public Health, working in Edinburgh, Leeds, the USA (University of Michigan) before moving to Lyon, France, join the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) in 1981, where he became head of the department of Descriptive Epidemiology. He remained in Lyon for 23 years, publishing extensively on cancer epidemiology, notably on geographic patterns and trends, as well as on evaluation of cancer screening.</p>

<p>In 2004 he returned to UK, and joined CTSU as Honorary Senior Research Fellow, and in 2005 the Wolfson Institute, Queen Mary University of London. He continues his association with the IARC as Senior Visiting Scientist, in order to coordinate the activities of cancer registries in Africa. The latter work is through the African Network of Cancer Registries, which was founded in 2011 with a grant from the Doris Duke cancer Foundation, USA. This project is managed through the Oxford-based NGO “INCTR Challenge Fund”</p>

<p>Dr Parkin is Foreign Adjunct Professor at the Karolinska Institute, Stockholm and  honorary professor at the Universities of Peking (Beijing) and Tianjin, China, and has been awarded  honorary doctorates by the University of Tampere (Finland)and Queen Mary University of London. He is a member of the editorial board of several international journals, and has published extensively, with more than 400 papers and reviews in the international scientific literature, mainly on descriptive epidemiology (international cancer patterns and trends), with a major concern for cancer registration, and in cancer prevention and control (especially the effectiveness of cancer screening).</p>
]]></hub_pi>
	<canreg_experts> Guy N'da (Ivory Coast), Gladys Chesumbai Onyango (Kenya) </canreg_experts>
	<planned_activities><![CDATA[
<p> The monograph, Cancer of Childhood in Africa, is in press.<br/>
    Research projects such as Treatment and Outcome study and survival study (SurvCan 3) are ongoing in around 15 member registries. <br/>
    The Swaziland National Cancer Registry (SNCR) is set to join the AFCRN, on a provisional base, and become its 31st member. </p> ]]></planned_activities>
	
</country>